<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Hyperplex</title>
		<description>A blog by Daniel Aditya Istyana which will talk about technology and news arounds Apple. Sometimes you've nothing to read here and of course it leads nowhere.</description>
		<link>http://hyperplex.co</link>
		<atom:link href="http://hyperplex.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Get Additional Hours Usage From Your Mac by Using Safari</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;We all know and admit that Chrome is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3schools.com/browsers/browsers_stats.asp&quot;&gt;the most popular browser&lt;/a&gt; in the world with approximately make 64.8% of internet visit. But there’s not a secret anymore that Chrome has issues with its memory management. Chrome. It eats your RAM and memory of your laptop/ PC and that’s why extensions such us &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/klbibkeccnjlkjkiokjodocebajanakg&quot;&gt;The Great Suspender&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/onetab/chphlpgkkbolifaimnlloiipkdnihall&quot;&gt;OneTab&lt;/a&gt; exist to reduce this annoyances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use Chrome at work and the memory management issue on Chrome is really bad. It’s not just slowing Chrome itself but the entire computer and sometimes make other program not responding when I open too many tabs&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:fn1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Since I use it on PC, there’s no problem with battery usage&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:fn2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but when you use it on PC or Mac you should think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.getbatterybox.com/which-browser-is-the-most-energy-efficient-chrome-vs-safari-vs-firefox/&quot;&gt;BatteryBox recently published&lt;/a&gt; numbers from their experiment comparing power consumption of three major browser, Safari, Firefox, and Chrome on Macbook. The result, Safari is the most efficient than other two with average 6 hours and 21 minutes of total usage. Chrome, of course, gets on the third place with just 5 hours 8 min of total usage when you use it on Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a surprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;http://macsparky.com/&quot;&gt;MacSparky&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Clearly, preserving battery life on all of its devices is a high priority for Apple. I’d venture to say that because Apple is the hardware vendor, preserving battery life always will be higher on Apple’s list than Google’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:fn1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Less than 20 if it’s not too many &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:fn1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:fn2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Obviously &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:fn2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 10:50:00 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/article/2015/08/get-additional-hours-usage-from-your-mac-by-using-safari/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/article/2015/08/get-additional-hours-usage-from-your-mac-by-using-safari/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Visual History of the iTunes Icon</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Reda Lemeden showed us how iTunes’ icon evolve through years. That memories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 22:47:10 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/08/a-visual-history-of-the-itunes-icon/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/08/a-visual-history-of-the-itunes-icon/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Radio Ad Script For The Apple IIC</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Nostalgic!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 18:27:05 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/08/radio-ad-script-for-the-apple-iic/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/08/radio-ad-script-for-the-apple-iic/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Former Apple artist Susan Kare joins Pinterest as a lead product designer</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you grew up using a Mac — or have any connection with computer graphics or design — the name Susan Kare will be familiar. She is the one who created the original Macintosh icons like the Lasso, the Grabber and the Paint Bucket, as well as the operating system’s typefaces like Chicago — which was also used for the iPod.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Today, Pinterest has announced that Kare is joining its creative team as a product design lead. In this full-time permanent position, Kare will be one of the designers responsible for the interface and design of products for the Pinterest website and apps.  She will report to Bob Baxley, head of product design — also an Apple alum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/08/former-apple-artist-susan-kare-joins-pinterest-as-a-lead-product-designer/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/08/former-apple-artist-susan-kare-joins-pinterest-as-a-lead-product-designer/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Apple Music Matches Files with Metadata Only, not Acoustic Fingerprinting</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Kirk McElhearn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is a very big problem with Apple Music. Since Apple already has the technology to match tracks using acoustic fingerprinting, they should be using this with Apple Music. Instead, it’s using scattershot matching, which results in lots of tracks showing up as being from different albums, from compilations, or totally different versions of songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/article/2015/07/the-apple-music-sad-story/&quot;&gt;The sad story of Apple Music&lt;/a&gt; seems continue with the big problem of matching music method they use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 08:58:00 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/08/apple-music-matches-files-with-metadata-only-not-acoustic-fingerprinting/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/08/apple-music-matches-files-with-metadata-only-not-acoustic-fingerprinting/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>iTunes Is the Locus of Everything Apple Is Doing Wrong</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Khoi Vinh:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On just one level, the application is an executional mess that speaks to the company’s worrying inattention to detail. iTunes is slow and bloated; it’s a terrible, poky, unreliable network client; it’s embedded into the operating system and yet works well with few other apps; its management of iOS devices (for those who don’t use iCloud) is painfully inelegant. And if all that weren’t enough, it just looks incredibly ugly. […] How much can one expect from the most profitable company in history? It’s certainly not asking too much for iTunes, which is in so many ways the front door for the Apple ecosystem, to be less of a shabby doorway and more of a grand entrance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 15:42:47 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/itunes-is-the-locus-of-everything-apple-is-doing-wrong/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/itunes-is-the-locus-of-everything-apple-is-doing-wrong/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Reeder 3 for Mac</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;My favorite applications to follow blogs and latest news, Reeder 3 for Mac now enters public beta. The most noticeable changes is now Reeder 3 bring flatter and blurry OS X Yosemite looks. If you living dangerously with installing OS X El Capitan just like me, Reeder 3 also supports the new San Francisco fonts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 10:21:00 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/reeder-30-for-mac-public-beta/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/reeder-30-for-mac-public-beta/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Security Writer Says Goodbye to Android</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Security writer from Motherboard, Lorenzo Franceschi-Bicchierai:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is the fundamental difference between Android and iPhone. When there’s a bug on iOS, Apple patches it and can push an update to all iPhone users as soon as it’s ready, no questions asked.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When the same thing happens with Android, Google patches and then… god knows when the AT&amp;amp;Ts, Verizons, HTCs, and Sonys of the world will decide it’s important enough that they should care and send you the update with the patch (though to their credit, they’re starting to care, mostly because having an updated OS is now seen as a competitive advantage). Hell, even Google-owned Nexus phones, which the company has full control over, haven’t been patched for Stagefright yet.[…]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You can keep your Android phone with that modified version of Android that your carrier or manufacturer has decided to put on it, and get security updates weeks late, or never (if you have a Nexus you’re better off, but who knows if Google is going to keep making Nexus phones in the future).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Or you can root your phone and install the excellent and more swiftly updated Android-based operating system CyanogenMod on it. This is a good alternative, but it’s not trivial to install CyanogenMod, and updates for certain phones depend on volunteers, so, again, you might not get them as soon as you’d wish.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Or, lastly, you can give up, switch to Apple and buy an iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;As much as my old self will hate me, I’m going to choose the last option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I know it sucks when you have to join the dark side you hate but at least now you safe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 20:00:02 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/a-security-writer-says-goodbye-to-android/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/a-security-writer-says-goodbye-to-android/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Why I Don't Read Email in the Morning</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/roidrage&quot;&gt;Mathias Mayer&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Try this out for a week. Instead of opening email in the morning, open your notebook and write down two or three tasks that you want to get done before lunch. Then work through them. What you can get done in just two hours and by focusing only on work is pure magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why you don’t have to open and get inbox zero at the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 15:30:00 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/why-i-dont-read-email-in-the-morning/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/why-i-dont-read-email-in-the-morning/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Hide preference panes from System Preferences</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A nice little tip by Dan Morren about hiding preference panes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/tip-hide-preference-panes-from-system-preferences/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/tip-hide-preference-panes-from-system-preferences/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
